## **VIMAL T ALOXIOUS**



## **Summary**

Presently working as a Factory Supervisor with Al Furat Refrigeration and Thermal Insulation Industry LLC.

I worked as a Graphic Designer with Deccan Chronicle Holdings Ltd., a famous English News Daily in India. I have more than Eleven years' experience.

## Skill Highlights

- Highly Motivated
- Ability to handle pressure & meet deadlines
- Leadership Skills
- Good interpersonal skills

- Creative design
- Flexible
- Mangement and Organisational skills
- Attention to detail
- Teamwork skills

## Experience

Factory Supervisor - Since 12/2019 in UAE.

Al Furat Refrigeration and Thermal Insulation Industry LLC.

- Weekly preparation of job schedule.
- Wholly responsible for all equipments, machines, tools etc.
- Necessary co-ordination with Factory Departments in executing the planned schedules and achieving the desired job completion dates.

- Transportation arrangement for staff / sites.
- Necessary co-ordination with GA towards registration / accidents / repairs of all commercial vehicles in the company.
- Necessary correspondence with HR Dept. concerning factory staff.
- Weekly meetings to be conducted in the presence of GM & Floor supervisors.
- Ensure compliance to company's policies and procedures in office / factory related activities.

**Graphic Designer** -04/2008 to 12/2018 in Chennai (Page Designing, Page Layout Design) 12/2018 to 12/2019 in Kochi (Page Designing, Interaction with clients, Explaining the advertisement details & important to clients. Logo & Icon designing for Pages ) **Deccan Chronicle Holdings Ltd.** 

- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Work with Editorial Designers to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Complete detailed Page Layout and Designing tasks for Editorial.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

### Graphic Designer - Lopez Design Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi, from January 2008 to March 2008.

- Tracing Pictures in Adobe Illustrator.
- Designing Logos and Brochures.

### Education

Bachelor of Arts: **English Literature** – 2015.

Madurai Kamaraj University

**Diploma in Graphic Designing**— 2002. Don Bosco Technical Institute, New Delhi Known Softwares: **Adobe Photoshop, CorelDraw, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, QuarkXpress**.

### Contact

#### Address:

Thazhchayil (H)

Mannanam P.O.

Kottayam

Kerala

Pin- 686 561

#### Phone:

+971 52 897 3549

### Email:

vimaldote@gmail.com

# Languages

English Hindi Malayalam

# Personal Details

Date of Birth: 22/05/1984

Sex: Male

Nationality: Indian Religion: Christian

Marital Status: Married

Languages Known: Malayalam, English & Hindi